# **Shivam Bhasin**

### Full Stack Developer

Experienced Web and Android Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the public policy industry. Skilled in Java, Android, Spring Boot, MySql, MongoDb, Flutter and Public Speaking. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology focused in Computer Science from Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida.

## Skills

#### Overview



### **Programming**

 $0\ LOC \longrightarrow 5000\ LOC$ 

Java • Android • MySql

Python • Flutter(Dart)0 • MongoDB

C C++ • NodeJS • PostgreSql

### **Contact**



8130583124



shivamvk.github.io



16103223shivam@gmail.com



/in/shivam-bhasin-69a588158



shivamvk

### **Education**

2016 - 2020\* **BTech, Computer Science** (GPA: 6.4 / 10) Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

2016 Intemediate, Science and Maths (CBSE score: 94.4 % ) St. Francis Convent School, Bareilly

### **Projects**

Job in tree Java Backend

Job search and recommendations by picking keywords from the resume uploaded as pdf and using machine learning.

- Created REST Api's for the project on Spring boot and MongoDb.
- Also managed the AWS EC2 instance for database and server.
- Tools: Java, MongoDb, Spring, Android, Machine Learning, AWS
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/JobInTree-Server

Snipped Full Stack

A salon service booking app built with modern day UI/UX on flutter.

• Created the complete frontend on Google's latest mobile technol-

- ogy Flutter.
- Created the backend with Spring Boot and MongoDb.
- Hosted the backend on AWS EC2 instance and also managed the database on the server.
- Tools: Java, Flutter, MongoDb, Spring, AWS
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/Snipped-Mobile
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/Snipped-Server

## **Experience**

Jun 2019 - **Java** Jul 2019

Java Backend Developer

Aedilics, Noida

- Made complete backend for Aedilics on Java using latest technologies like Spring Boot, Hibernate and MongoDB.
- Also took care of the AWS EC2 instance provided by the project lead.

Oct 2018 -Jan 2019 Google Code-in Mentor

JBoss, RedHat

- Was a member of a team of 40 people selected from around the globe to mentor in Google code-in for JBoss, RedHat.
- We as a team created tasks for participants before the Google Codein started. After that evaluated several submissions and also dealt with the participants' doubts.

Jul 2018 -Oct 2018 **Full Stack Developer** 

Mindful Machine, Noida

- Created 3 android apps for Mindful Machine. The three apps included the customer app, shopkeeper's app and the admin app.
- Also created the backend from scratch using Spring boot and MongoDb.

Jan 2018 -Feb 2018 Frontend Developer

HiddenRamp, Delhi

- Worked on their website to improve UI/UX.
- Used technologies like CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery and AJAX.